Making waves in our world.
The SpongeBob Movie: Sponge Out of Water is a family,
comedy, adventure film directed by Paul Tibbitt.
Burger Beard is a pirate who is in search of the final page of a magical book that makes any evil
plan he writes in it come true, which happens to be the Krabby Patty secret formula.
When the entire city of Bikini Bottom is put in danger, SpongeBob, Patrick, Mr.
Krabs, Squidward, Sandy, and Plankton need to go on a
quest that takes them to the surface.
In order to get back the recipe and save their city, the gang must
retrieve the book and transform themselves into superheroes.
SpongeBob / Gary / Agreeable Mob Member / Waffle (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
Patrick / Male Fish / Eager Customer (voice), played by Bill Fagerbakke.
Doctor / Squidward / Angry Mob Member #2 / Doughnut /
Squidasaurus Rex (voice), played by Rodger Bumpass.
Mr. Krabs (voice), played by Clancy Brown.
Plankton / Plankton Robot / News Anchor Fish / Mob
Member (voice), played by Mr. Lawrence.
Sandy (voice), played by Carolyn Lawrence.
The SpongeBob Movie: Search for SquarePants is a 2025 American animated adventure comedy film
based on the SpongeBob SquarePants television series, created by Stephen Hillenburg.
Directed by series veteran Derek Drymon, it stars the show's regular voice cast alongside
George Lopez, Ice Spice, Arturo Castro, Sherry Cola, Regina Hall, and Mark Hamill.
The plot follows SpongeBob on a quest to prove his bravery by adventuring with
the ghost pirate, The Flying Dutchman, through the Underworld.
It is the fourth theatrical film based on the series, following
2020's Sponge on the Run, and the sixth film overall.
The film was written by Pam Brady and Matt Lieberman, from a story by
Brady and series creatives Marc Ceccarelli and Kaz.
It was first developed as a direct-to-streaming film focused on Mr.
Krabs, but the project was later retooled into a theatrical
feature with SpongeBob as the lead character instead.
By April 2023, Drymon had been hired to direct the film.
In July 2024, Hamill was revealed to be voicing the Flying
Dutchman in the film in place of Brian Doyle-Murray.
John Debney composed the film's score, after having
previously scored 2015's Sponge Out of Water.
Search for SquarePants premiered at the AFI Film Festival on October 26, 2025, before holding a premiere in New York City
on December 17, and was theatrically released by Paramount Pictures in the United States on December 19.
The film received mostly positive reviews from critics
and has grossed $153.5 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of sea, ocean, villain, sequel, computer animation.
The tone is lighthearted.